# CHRISSIE AKAU

## WEB DEVELOPER



505-417-3668



cakau9@gmail.com



Los Angeles, CA || Remote



linkedin.com/in/chrissieakau



github.com/chrissie-akau

#### PORTFOLIO



chrissie-akau.github.io

## SKILLS

<u>Languages</u>: JavaScript, Ruby, SQL, HTML, CSS

Frameworks: React, Ruby on Rails

<u>Databases</u>: PostgreSQL, Active Record

Testing: JEST, RSPEC, Enzyme

Version Control: Git

### **Editing, Motion Graphics, and**

**Design**: Adobe Premiere, Adobe After Effects, Adobe Photoshop, Final Cut X and 7, Davinci

**Soft Skills:** Creativity, flexibility, leadership, empathy, optimism, communication, enthusiasm, critical thinking, teamwork, active listening, love of learning, ability to learn quickly

## EDUCATION

## Bachelor's Degree in Fine Arts Film and TV Production Cum Laude

Loyola Marymount University 2006 – 2010

## SUMMARY

Full stack software developer who uses test-driven development to write efficient and user-friendly code. Creative self-starter with 10+ years of entrepreneurial experience in the entertainment industry. Highly collaborative with unique perspective and problem-solving abilities. Passionate about accessibility and producing engaging, intuitive products.

## EXPERIENCE

## **Full Stack Web Developer Student**

LEARN Academy / April 2020 - Present

- 500+ hours of direct coding experience in an intensive web development bootcamp
- Gaining proficiency with building full stack applications using JavaScript, React, Ruby, and Ruby on Rails
- Utilizing test-driven development to produce efficient and bug-free code
- Collaborating and communicating effectively on mob and pair programming projects
- TA for JumpStart weekend, teaching prospective LEARN students the fundamentals of HTML, CSS, and JavaScript

#### Freelance Producer/Director/Editor/Videographer

Good Egg Productions LLC / December 2009 - Present

- Create promotional videos and content for client social media accounts and websites
- Manage projects through pre-production, production, and post-production phases
- Build realistic budgets for the creative scope of the projects and track accordingly
- Adapt and learn new techniques, technologies, and advancements in the industry

## VFX PA for Westworld Season 3

HBO Entertainment and Bad Robot Productions / August 2019 – October 2019

- Analyzed each shot and determined optimal placement of markers/trackers to guide post-VFX team on CGI implementation
- Self-taught and set up new technology motion capture suit and associated software and served as point person for troubleshooting
- Captured 360-degree photos of the set and talent to be referenced by post-VFX team
- Organized footage for deliverable drives under pressure with quick turnaround

## **Technical Editor**

## Roundabout Entertainment Inc. / July 2013 - October 2016

- Digitized tapes and created master files for Disney/ABC, 20<sup>th</sup> Television, NBC-Universal, Amazon, and Netflix features and syndication
- Worked with advanced file encoding and transcoding workflows including frame rate and standards conversions
- Developed efficient workflows for client deliverables

### **Technical Director**

Velocity Dance Convention/ July 2012-February 2013

- Configured live broadcasting video system used during convention performances
- Created all visual content for company website and social media
- Captured and edited footage from classes and competition into sizzle reels